James Michael Galantino

Middle Island, NY 11953

james.mgalantino@gmail.com o (631) 374 0059

https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-galantino-0aab6a16a/ https://github.com/jimbopulos https://james-galantino-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a music and audio engineering background sincerely interested in promoting positive environmental change via Software Engineering. Recently received a certificate from Columbia University's Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, where concrete capabilities in CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and back-end development were established. Fast learner with reliable work ethic and sense of humor. Works responsibly and diligently on their own, as well as in a team, with a strong sense of communication and considerate collaboration. In a recent project, utilized front-end and back-end technologies, API's, MongoDB storage, and JavaScript. Worked with two other developers to deliver to users a service that allows them to manage their garden accounts and maintain plant health. Genuinely looking forward to being a contributor in constructing valuable virtual utilities essential in the future of global climate science, renewable energy and the acquisition of its goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Azure cloud computing resources/infrastructure
- CSS3 and associated frameworks (Bootstrap, etc.)
- JavaScript, ¡Query, Node.js, Express.js, React.js
- HTML5
- MySQL
- MongoDB

- Git
- Progressive web apps
- Proficient in Pro Tools, Logic & Digital Performer
- Song Writer/Composer
- Recording Technician

PROJECTS

Trowel Web App | https://trowel-app.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Full-stack MERN application tailored for gardeners, gardening businesses, to manage accounts and ensure proper plant maintenance in each account.
- Role: Front-end and Back-end Developer, Project Manager, Styling
- Technologies:
 - o HTML
 - CSS and Bootstrap
 - JavaScript
 - o MongoDB, Mongoose
 - Express.js
 - o React.js
 - Node.js
 - Trefle API
 - Passport

Pipe Cleaner Web App | https://four-top.herokuapp.com/

• Description: utilized MySQL and Sequelize to deliver to users an application that allows for meal and respective ingredient logging, with the ability to add potentially problematic items to a 'Watch List'.

- Role: Front-end Developer, Styling
- Technologies:
 - HTML/Handlebars
 - CSS and Bulma
 - JavaScript
 - o MySQL, Sequelize
 - o Express.js
 - Node.js
 - Passport

Rec Web Application | https://jimbopulos.github.io/rec-app/

- Description: leveraged multiple API's to generate both a music recommendation and visual media based on a user's mood or activity engagement.
- Role: Developer, API data parsing, Design
- Technologies:
 - o HTML
 - o CSS and Semantic UI
 - JavaScript, jQuery
 - Web API: TheAudioMusicDB and Owl Carousel

WORK EXPERIENCE

School of Rock Instructor, Port Jefferson Station, NY

September 2018 – December 2020

- Piano Instructor teaching individual lessons
- Provided students with extensive Music Theory knowledge and performance skills to prepare them for both tribute shows and professional careers in music
- Transcribed wide catalogue of work to presents students with neatly written sheet music for the purpose of practicing their music and improving their own playing/reading skills
- Coordinated and directed tribute show in which students rehearse to play publicly at a venue so that they may obtain real firsthand experience of performing in front of a live audience

Coral Restaurant and Tapas Bar Food Runner and Expo, East Moriches, NY

July 2017 - July 2018

- Food runner for a newly opened water front restaurant
- Kitchen exposition, plate decoration and preparation
- Extreme focus on customer service as well as overall client experience to ensure a holistically ideal restaurant atmosphere

La Bistro Delivery, Coram, NY

May 2016 - August 2016

- Delivery driver for Pizzeria
- Performed various duties such as food prep, stocking, and store clean-up to maintain an efficient and health-code abiding kitchen
- Transported resources and machines between multiple store locations in order to guarantee a smooth and efficient restaurant workflow, in the event of equipment failures or shortages

Jildor Shoes Salesman, Southampton, NY

May 2015 – August 2015

- Floor salesman for Men's Shoe section of store
- Kept inventory on footwear/accessory stock to keep shelves populated with products for purchase, as well as remaining accessible for fellow employees and staff
- Organized items by brand, size, condition for the goal of demonstrating a clear and professional sales floor

• Dedication to properly fitting customers and assisted in style selection with the intent of serving a client exactly what they desired

PERSONAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Honest, driven, trustworthy & excellent communicator
- Piano, Guitar, Drums
- Archery, Lacrosse, Soccer, Yoga
- Creative Writing, Art

EDUCATION

Columbia University School of Engineering - Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Certified - AZ-900 SUNY New Paltz – State University of New York March 2021 October 2020 May 2018

Bachelor of Science, Music with a concentration in Recording & Electronic Music Dean's List – all semesters
Outstanding Graduate Award